<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Prashant K. Jha</title>
    <link>https://prashjha.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://prashjha.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 [Prashant K. Jha](https://prashjha.github.io/)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://prashjha.github.io/images/logo_hu1c9a7bdcb0202df981fee96563257bac_112200_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://prashjha.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational methods for nonlocal models</title>
      <link>https://prashjha.github.io/project/computational-peridynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashjha.github.io/project/computational-peridynamics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Develop efficient and parallel computational methods for class of nonlocal models such as Peridynamics and nonlocal diffusion equations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-google-summer-of-code-2020&#34;&gt;1. Google Summer of Code 2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the development of a massively parallel computational library for peridynamics and other nonlocal models, together with P. Diehl, we prepared a computational problem where the goal was to develop a massively parallel library for the simple 2D nonlocal heat equation. See the rough description of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nonlocalmodels/nonlocalheatequation/blob/master/description/problem_description.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;problem&lt;/a&gt;. This project was sponsored by Google in Google Summer of Code 2020 and was assigned to student P. Gadikar (IIT Madras). Pranav&amp;rsquo;s work is open source and can be found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nonlocalmodels/nonlocalheatequation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Conference paper on proposed load balancing algorithm is in this link 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://prashjha.github.io/publication/gadikar-2021-nonlocal/&#34;&gt;GSoC 2020 conference paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-nlmech-library&#34;&gt;2. NLMech library&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have launched peridynamics code 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nonlocalmodels/NLMech&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NLMech&lt;/a&gt; that utilizes 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/STEllAR-GROUP/hpx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HPX&lt;/a&gt; library for efficient multi-threading computation. We aim to make the NLMech library more user-friendly and easily extensible in the coming days. Our future goals are to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;develop a fully parallel library following some of the key ideas and algorithms from our GSoC 2020 work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;implement Quasistatic discretization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper with P. Diehl briefly describing the open-source library is currently under review in JOSS (Journal of Open Source Software). The review of the code and paper is open and can be seen live 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openjournals/joss-reviews/issues/2898&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis and application of peridynamics</title>
      <link>https://prashjha.github.io/project/fracture-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashjha.github.io/project/fracture-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-kinetic-relations-and-local-energy-balance-for-lefm-from-a-nonlocal-peridynamic-model&#34;&gt;1. Kinetic relations and local energy balance for LEFM from a nonlocal peridynamic model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work, we carefully looked at the peridynamic energy associated with the process zone. We recovered the kinetic relation for crack tip velocity for the mode-I crack problem. It is based on more theoretical work; see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://prashjha.github.io/publication/lipton-2020-plane/&#34;&gt;Lipton and Jha 2021&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://prashjha.github.io/publication/jha-2020-peri/&#34;&gt;Jha and Lipton 2020&lt;/a&gt;. This is joint work with Dr. R. Lipton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some interesting simulations are shown next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/mode-I_IntJFra.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Simulation of Mode-I propagation. We apply vertically outward displacement boundary conditions on the small layer in the top and bottom. Material has initial pre-crack. Simulation from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10704-020-00480-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/mixed_mode_alex.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/crack_and_void_alex.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inclined crack propagation. We apply diagonally outward force in small regions near the right-top and left-bottom corner. Simulation from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s42102-019-00010-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;. Here red indicates a node with one or more broken bonds in its neighborhood.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crack propagation in the presence of the void. We see that void deflects the crack moving straight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-a-priori-error-analysis-and-well-posedness-of-nonlinear-peridynamic-models&#34;&gt;2. A priori error analysis and well-posedness of nonlinear peridynamic models&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Louisiana State University, I had spent a good amount of time working on &lt;em&gt;a priori&lt;/em&gt; error estimates for finite-difference and finite-element discretization of and well-posedness of nonlinear peridynamic models. This was under the guidance of my adviser Dr. R. Lipton. On this topic, we have published several journal articles and few book chapters, see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://prashjha.github.io/publication/&#34;&gt;publication page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that peridynamics regularizes the discontinuity; the sharp edge of discontinuity is replaced with the softening zone containing material points with large strains (classical strain). Away from the softening zone, the strains are smaller. Typically the size of the softening zone is proportional to the nonlocal length scale. As the nonlocal length scale goes to zero, the softening zone localizes to a sharp crack. To demonstrate this, we consider a setup shown in Figure 1. In Figure 2, we plot the damage for three different nonlocal length scales at two times. We see that for a smaller nonlocal length scale, the softening zone indicated by the red region is smaller than that of a bigger nonlocal length scale. In Figure 3, we put the plots of three horizons on top of each other, and we see the localization of the softening zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/localization/setup.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/localization/Z_plots.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Setup for localization of softening zone. More details 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1908.07589&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;preprint, section 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Damage in material with three horizons at two times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/localization/Z_plots_overlap.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 3: Softening zone of three horizons when placed on top of each other. Light yellow, light orange, and red correspond to smaller, intermediate, and larger horizons. As the horizon is getting smaller softening zone is shrinking to a very thin region, and ultimately in the limit, it will tend to sharp crack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-model-development&#34;&gt;3. Model development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://prashjha.github.io/publication/lipton-2018-free/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;, we proposed a bond-based peridynamic model with memory effect. If the material is subjected to cyclic loading, with each cycle deforming the material beyond some critical strain, it will continue to lose stiffness in every loading cycle. This effect is simulated using the temporal nonlocal force (material strength at a current time depends on the history) in the proposed model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling tumor growth, angiogenesis, drug-therapy, metastasis</title>
      <link>https://prashjha.github.io/project/tumor-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashjha.github.io/project/tumor-modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-analysis-of-a-new-multispecies-tumor-growth-model-coupling-3d-phase-fields-with-a-1d-vascular-network&#34;&gt;1. Analysis of a new multispecies tumor growth model coupling 3D phase-fields with a 1D vascular network&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is joint work with Dr. J. T. Oden at UT Austin and colleagues at the Technical University of Munich. In this work, we study the 3D-1D model of tumor growth that couples the flow and transport of nutrients in the vessel network with nutrient and tumor evolution in the tissue domain. In particular, we looked at the well-posedness of the resulting highly coupled multi-dimension nonlinear model. See the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://prashjha.github.io/publication/fritz-2020-analysis/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 1 below shows progression of tumor towards nutrient rich artery on the right. In top row, the contour $\phi_T = 0.8$ plot of total tumor (sum of prolific, hypoxic, and necrotic) species volume fraction is shown. In bottom row, tumor sub-species, necrotic $\phi_N = 0.4$ (black), hypoxic $\phi_H = 0.45$ (orange), and prolific $\phi_P = 0.5$ (green), are shown. Figure is taken from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://prashjha.github.io/publication/fritz-2020-analysis/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/paper1/paper1-two-vessels.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Tumor growth towards nutrient rich artery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-modeling-and-simulation-of-vascular-tumors-embedded-in-dynamically-evolving-capillary-networks&#34;&gt;2. Modeling and simulation of vascular tumors embedded in dynamically evolving capillary networks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work takes the work in the paper above one step further. In this work, we add the angiogenesis effect to the model. Angiogenesis is a phenomenon through which nutrient-starved tumor cells release unique molecules collectively called TAF (Tumor Angiogenesis Factor), which co-opt the blood vessels in the vicinity to grow towards the tumor colony and supply nutrients. We recently submitted the work for review, see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://prashjha.github.io/publication/fritz-2021-angiogenesis/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 demonstrates the angiogenesis effect and simultaneous tumor growth. Figure 3 shows the quantity of interests such as total tumor $\phi_T$, prolific $\phi_P$, hypoxic $\phi_H$, and necrotic $\phi_N$ masses with or without angiogenesis. Since angiogenesis is stochastic, we run the simulation multiple times to capture the variation in QoIs. Figures 2 and 3 and simulation videos in this section are from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://prashjha.github.io/publication/fritz-2021-angiogenesis/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/paper2/paper2-angio.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Network growth for two-vessels and complex network settings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/paper2/paper2-two-vessels-QoIstats.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 3: Effect of angiogenesis on tumor associated quantity of interests&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/paper2/paper2_two_vessels/m1.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/paper2/paper2_two_vessels/m2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Angiogenesis simulation, two-vessels setup (sample 1)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Angiogenesis simulation, two-vessels setup (sample 2)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/paper2/paper2_complex/m1.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/paper2/paper2_complex/m2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Angiogenesis simulation, complex network setup (sample 1)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Angiogenesis simulation, complex network setup (sample 2)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-application-and-extension-of-the-3d-1d-model-of-tumor-growth&#34;&gt;3. Application and extension of the 3D-1D model of tumor growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we are interested in developing a tumor growth model to predict treatment responses and metastasis. For both of these problems, it is necessary to model the coupled flow in tissue and vasculature. We are extending the model to include the flow of drugs in vessels and tissue and its effect on tumor growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While our work so far has been concerned with algorithmic development and abstract simulations that highlight the key capabilities of the model, we are also interested in the model&amp;rsquo;s calibration using MRI data. Towards this, we are working with experts at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cco.oden.utexas.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Computational Oncology&lt;/a&gt; for the application of the multi-dimensional model to breast cancer. The vasculature, flow parameters, initial tumor region in our model will be based on MRI data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is known that the vessels formed as a result of angiogenesis are leaky and weak; the mechanical forces in the tissue microenvironment plays are role in the modification and destruction of these vessels. The mechanical effects are also observed in the growth of the tumor. We are also interested in adding a mechanical component to the model and coupling the mechanical forces with vessels&#39; displacement and tumor growth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal recovery from MRI</title>
      <link>https://prashjha.github.io/project/signal-recovery-tumor-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashjha.github.io/project/signal-recovery-tumor-modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-a-mechanistic-tumor-growth-model-for-hp-mri&#34;&gt;1. A mechanistic tumor growth model for HP MRI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to propose a PDE-based model for recovery of a parameter such as &lt;em&gt;pyruvate to lactate transfer rate&lt;/em&gt; from the Hyperpolarized (HP) MR imaging data. HP MRI is a state of art imaging technique and provides a means to identify the tumor regions. Pyruvate to lactate conversion naturally occurs in tissue; however, this conversion is typically more substantial in the presence of cancerous cells. HP MRI provides the intensity of pyruvate and lactate produced from polarized pyruvate. The region with high lactate indicates the presence of cancerous cells. Postprocessing of HP MRI data involves the calculation of &lt;em&gt;pyruvate to lactate transfer rate&lt;/em&gt;. Current models are based on spatially invariant compartmental models. Our objective is to propose a PDE-based model coupled with the vascular flow to describe pyruvate and lactate evolution. The vasculature will be based on real data. We believe that such a high-fidelity model will result in a more accurate recovery of parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, Oden Institute, MD Anderson Cancer Center, and TACC signed an MOU to advance cancer research. Our HP MRI project was selected as one of the five pilot projects under the joint initiative and will be effective from 09/01/2020 - 08/31/2021.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of granular media</title>
      <link>https://prashjha.github.io/project/granular-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashjha.github.io/project/granular-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-development-of-a-high-fidelity-model-for-granular-media&#34;&gt;1. Development of a high-fidelity model for granular media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking the earlier research on peridynamics for granular media forward, we have developed the Peridynamics-DEM high-fidelity model that can handle arbitrarily shaped particles and particle breakage. Traditional models based on DEM (Discrete Element Method) can not handle the particles with arbitrary shapes and deformation of individual particles. Extension of DEM based method to overcome these challenges is possible. However, it is not trivial. PeriDEM model proposed in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmps.2021.104376&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jha et al 2021&lt;/a&gt; uses peridynamics for deformation of individual particles. In the model, the contact forces between two particles act at the level of discretization. Because contact forces are applied to discretized nodes (within a small distance) of two particles, particles can see the local boundary; thus, the model can accurately simulate the locking effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/two_p_wall_fracture_m1_all.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Two-particle test. The top particle is given initial velocity. The plot shows the damage upon contact for different initial velocities—both particles made of the same materials. Damage above 1 indicates the onset of failure. From 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmps.2021.104376&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jha et al 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/two_p_wall_fracture_m12_all.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Same as Figure 1, but now the particle on top is stronger than the bottom particle. We see that only the bottom particle has damage above 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/compressive_test_reaction_force_n500.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 3: Compressive test using 502 circular and hexagon-shaped particles of varying sizes. The container&amp;rsquo;s top wall is moving downwards. &lt;strong&gt;Top&lt;/strong&gt;: Plot of reaction force on the container&amp;rsquo;s top wall as a function of penetration downwards. &lt;strong&gt;Bottom&lt;/strong&gt;: Damage on individual particles at different times. Damage on discretized nodes of particles is shown. Red indicates a node has damage one or above. From 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmps.2021.104376&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jha et al 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/m1_t5.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/m1_t6.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/m12_t5.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/m12_t6.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two particles with same properties. $v_0 = 4$ m/s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two particles with same properties. $v_0 = 5$ m/s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Top particle stronger than bottom. $v_0 = 4$ m/s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Top particle stronger than bottom. $v_0 = 5$ m/s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/two_particle_wall_concave_diff_material_diff_size.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fracture simulation with concave particles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;files/compressive_test.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Compressive test simulation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
